printerpix.com 2019-05-17

# 

**  
1\. Introduction**

1.1 We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of website visitors and customers of Printerpix.com, including its subdomains (collectively, the “Website”); in this privacy policy we explain how we collect and process your personal data through your use of the website.

1.2 This policy applies where we are acting as a data controller with respect to your personal data; in other words, where we determine the purposes and means of the processing of that personal data.

1.3 We use cookies on our website. Insofar as those cookies are not strictly necessary for the provision of our website and services.

1.4 Our website incorporates privacy controls which affect how we will process your personal data. By using the privacy controls, you can specify whether you would like to receive direct marketing communications. You can access the privacy controls via https://www.printerpix.com/account/edit/?justr=1.

1.5 It is important that you read this privacy policy together with any other privacy notice or fair processing notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This privacy notice supplements the other notices and is not intended to override them.

1.6 In this policy, "we", "us" and "our" refer to Printerpix UK Limited. For more information about us, see Section 1.

**  
2\. How we use your personal data**

2.1 In Section 2 we have set out:

(a) the general categories of personal data that we may process;

(b) the purposes for which we may process personal data; and

(c) the legal bases of the processing.

2.2 We may collect, use and store different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together as follows:

2.2.1 data about your use of our website and services ("usage data"). The usage data may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths, as well as information about the timing and frequency. This usage data may be processed for the purposes of analysing the use of the website and services.

2.2.2 data about your account ("account data"). The account data may include your name and email address. The source of the account data is you. The account data may be processed for the purposes of operating our website.

2.2.3 information relating to transactions, including purchases of goods through our website ("transaction data"). The transaction data may include your contact details, and the transaction details.

2.2.4 information that you provide to us for subscribing to our email newsletters ("notification data").

2.2.5 information contained in or relating to any communication that you send to us ("correspondence data"). The correspondence data may include the communication content and metadata associated with the communication. Our website will generate the metadata associated with communications made using the website contact forms.

2.3 We may process any of your personal data identified in this policy where necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the protection and assertion of our legal rights, your legal rights and the legal rights of others.

2.4 In addition to the specific purposes for which we may process your personal data set out in this Section 2, we may also process any of your personal data where such processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

2.5 We also collect, use and share Aggregated Data such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy policy.

2.6 We do not collect any Special Categories of Personal Data about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

If you fail to provide personal data

Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods or services). In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us, but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.

**  
3\. Providing your personal data to others**

3.1 We may disclose specific personal data to our suppliers or subcontractors insofar as reasonably necessary for manufacturing and dispatching your order.

3.2 Financial transactions relating to our website are handled by our payment services providers, (Paypal, Braintree or SagePay). We will share transaction data with our payment services providers only to the extent necessary for the purposes of processing your payments, refunding such payments and dealing with complaints and queries relating to such payments and refunds. You can find information about the payment services providers' privacy policies and practices at https://www.sagepay.com/policies/privacy-policy, https://www.paypal.com/uk/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full and https://www.braintreepayments.com/en-gb/legal/braintree-privacy-policy.

3.3 In addition to the specific disclosures of personal data set out in this Section 3, we may disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person. We may also disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure.

3.4 We may also have to share your personal data with third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy policy.

3.5 We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

**  
4\. International transfers of your personal data**

4.1 In Section 4, we provide information about the circumstances in which your personal data may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA).

4.2 We and our other group companies have offices and facilities in UK, USA and India. Transfers to each of these countries will be protected by appropriate safeguards, namely the use of standard data protection clauses adopted or approved by the European Commission.

4.3 The hosting facilities for our website are situated in UK.

4.4 Please contact us using our contact details in Section 17 if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA.

**  
5\. Data security**

5.1 We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

5.2 We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

**  
6\. Retaining and deleting personal data**

6.1 Section 6 sets out our data retention policies and procedure, which are designed to help ensure that we comply with our legal obligations in relation to the retention and deletion of personal data.

6.2 We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for.

6.3 Notwithstanding the other provisions of this Section 6, we may retain your personal data where such retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

6.4 To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements. Details of retention periods for different aspects of your personal data are available in our retention policy which you can request from us by contacting us using our contact details in section 16.

6.5 In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see [Request erasure] below for further information.

6.6 In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

**  
7\. Amendments**

7.1 We may update this policy from time to time by publishing a new version on our website.

7.2 You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes to this policy.

**  
8\. Your rights**

8.1 In this Section 8, we have summarised the rights that you have under data protection law. Some of the rights are complex, and not all of the details have been included in our summaries. Accordingly, you should read the relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities for a full explanation of these rights.

8.2 Your principal rights under data protection law are:

(a) the right to access;

(b) the right to rectification;

(c) the right to erasure;

(d) the right to restrict processing;

(e) the right to object to processing;

(f) the right to data portability;

(g) the right to complain to a supervisory authority; and

(h) the right to withdraw consent.

8.3 You have the right to confirmation as to whether we process your personal data and, where we do, access to the personal data, together with certain additional information. That additional information includes details of the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data concerned and the recipients of the personal data. Providing the rights and freedoms of others are not affected, we will supply to you a copy of your personal data. The first copy will be provided free of charge, but additional copies may be subject to a reasonable fee. We may also charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances. You can access your personal data by logging in and visiting https://www.printerpix.com/account/edit/?justr=1.

8.4 You have the right to have any inaccurate personal data about you rectified and, taking into account the purposes of the processing, to have any incomplete personal data about you completed.

8.5 In some circumstances you have the right to the erasure of your personal data without undue delay. Those circumstances include: the personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed; you withdraw consent to consent-based processing; you object to the processing under certain rules of applicable data protection law; the processing is for direct marketing purposes. However, there are exclusions of the right to erasure. The general exclusions include where processing is necessary: for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information; for compliance with a legal obligation; or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

8.6 In some circumstances you have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data. Those circumstances are: if you contest the accuracy of the personal data; processing is unlawful but you oppose erasure; we no longer need the personal data for the purposes of our processing, but you require personal data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; and you have objected to processing, pending the verification of that objection. Where processing has been restricted on this basis, we may continue to store your personal data. However, we will only otherwise process it: with your consent; for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person; or for reasons of important public interest.

8.7 You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data on the grounds relating to your particular situation, but only to the extent that the legal basis for the processing is that the processing is necessary for: the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of any official authority vested in us; or the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party. If you make such an objection, we will cease to process the personal information unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

8.8 You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes (including profiling for direct marketing purposes). If you make such an objection, we will cease to process your personal data for this purpose.

8.9 You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes on grounds relating to your particular situation, unless the processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out for reasons of public interest.

8.10 To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal data is:

(a) consent; or

(b) that the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are party or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract, and such processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive your personal data from us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. However, this right does not apply where it would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.

8.11 If you consider that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner's Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues (www.ico.org.uk). We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us in the first instance.

8.12 To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal information is consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. Withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of processing before the withdrawal.

8.13 You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data by written notice to us on email to dataprotection@printerpix.com in addition to the other methods specified in Section 17.

**  
9\. Third party websites**

9.1 Our website includes hyperlinks to, and details of, third party websites.

9.2 We have no control over, and are not responsible for, the privacy policies and practices of third parties.

**  
10\. Personal data of children**

10.1 Our website is targeted at persons over the age of 16 and we do not knowingly collect data relating to persons under the age of 16.

10.2 If we have reason to believe that we hold personal data of a person under that age in our databases, we will delete that personal data.

**  
11\. Updating information**

11.1 It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please let us know if the personal data that we hold about you needs to be corrected or updated.

**  
12\. About cookies**

12.1 A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.

12.2 Cookies may be either "persistent" cookies or "session" cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set an expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.

12.3 Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

**  
13\. Cookies that we use**

13.1 We use cookies for the following purposes:

(a) authentication - we use cookies to identify you when you visit our website and as you navigate our website (cookies used for this purpose are: Google Analytics, Visual Website Optimizer);

(b) status - we use cookies to help us to determine if you are logged into our website (cookies used for this purpose are: Printerpix);

(c) shopping cart - we use cookies to maintain the state of your shopping cart as you navigate our website (cookies used for this purpose are: Printerpix, Cloud-IQ);

(d) personalisation - we use cookies to store information about your preferences and to personalise our website for you (cookies used for this purpose are: Printerpix);

(e) advertising - we use cookies to help us to display advertisements that will be relevant to you. Cookies used for this purpose are: Double-Click, Cloud-IQ, Facebook, Google AdWords and Bing Ads;

(f) analysis - we use cookies to help us to analyse the use and performance of our website and services. Cookies used for this purpose are: Google Analytics, Visual Website Optimizer; and

(g) cookie consent - we use cookies to store your preferences in relation to the use of cookies more generally cookies used for this purpose are:

Printerpix.

**  
14\. Cookies used by our service providers**

14.1 Our service providers use cookies and those cookies may be stored on your computer when you visit our website.

14.2 We use Google Analytics to analyse the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google's privacy policy is available at: https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/. The relevant cookies are: analytics.js cookie.

**  
15\. Managing cookies**

15.1 Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:

(a) https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en (Chrome);

(b) https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences (Firefox);

(c) http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/ (Opera);

(d) https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies (Internet Explorer);

(e) https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411 (Safari); and

(f) https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy (Edge).

15.2 Blocking all cookies will have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites.

15.3 If you block cookies, you will not be able to use all the features on our website.

**  
16\. Cookie preferences**

16.1 You can manage your preferences relating to the use of cookies on your browser.

**  
17\. Our details**

17.1 This Website is owned and operated by Printerpix UK Limited.

17.2 We are registered in England and Wales under registration number 09509388, and our registered office is at Suite 1, Congress House, 14 Lyon road, Harrow, HA1 2EN.

17.3 Our principal place of business is at 107 Commerce Street, Lake Mary, FL 32746-6206, USA

17.4 You can contact us:

(a) by post, to the postal address given above;

(b) using our Website contact form;

(c) by telephone, on 1-888-322-6733; or

(d) by email, using contactus@printerpix.com.
